<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Aashray&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Aashray&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 08:40:29 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Build a Router Part 2</title>
      <link>/posts/lets-build-a-router-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 08:40:29 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lets-build-a-router-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back! If you followed part 1 of this series, then we’ll be answering a lot of the questions you may have had from last time, and if not, I’d highly suggest reading part 1 before we continue our journey to building a router.
To recap, we’ve set up our 3 virtual networks, and we’ve configured a router with one network adapter connected to the switches of each private network, and a 4th network adapter connected to a switch shared with our host machine’ network adapter, thus exposing Internet access to our router.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Build A Router Part 1</title>
      <link>/posts/lets-build-a-router-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 17:15:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lets-build-a-router-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Today I’m going to describe the first steps of how I set up a virtual router, to connect multiple private local access networks of virtual machines together, and eventually, to the Internet.
Obviously, we first need to understand, what is a router? It’s something we all have in our homes, but in the eyes of most, is just a magical tunnel to the Internet.
A router is really just a computer, which is specially configured to enable a set of devices to use a shared connection to the public internet (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
